（ハチマキ）ハァ ハァ ハァ…
ハァ ハァ…
んっ ハァ…
ハァ ハァ ハァ…
（心臓の音）
（ハチマキ）くっ… ああ…
Crap!
くそ！
（ハチマキ）
タナベ！ 俺が見えるか？
見えたら返事しろ！
Tanabe! Can you see me?!
If you can see me, answer me!
Please respond! Somebody!
答えてくれえ 誰かーっ！
Is anybody
out there?!
誰もいないのかーっ！
誰でもいい 答えてくれえーっ！
Anybody! Come in!
I'm here! I'm right over here!
俺はここだ ここにいるぞ！
Please, find me!
俺を見つけてくれえーっ！
ああっ くっ…
Somebody!
誰かああああーっ！
♪～
Soshite hito wa toki wo koeta yume wo miru
And people dream dreams that transcend time.
♪そして人は時空(とき)を
越えた夢を見る
seijyaku no umi ni idakarete
Held in the depths of the sea.
♪静寂の宇宙(うみ)に抱かれて
tori ya kumo wo miagete wa
As they look up at the stars and clouds.
♪鳥や雲を見上げては
hakanai inochi moyashita ikusen no asa ni
It set their ephemeral souls on fire on a thousand mornings.
♪儚(はかな)い生命(いのち)燃やした
♪幾千の朝に
hikari ga mukau basho he habataku darou
I bet they're taking right to where the light is headed.
♪光が向かう場所へ
♪羽ばたくだろう
daichi wo ima tori yoku kette
Now kickoff from the ground like a bird.
♪願いを放つ時は今
hatenaki yume wo noseta furontia he
Off into the frontier that is carrying boundless dreams.
♪果てなき夢を乗せた
♪フロンティアへ
tooku tooku dive in the sky
Farther and farther dive in the sky.
♪遠く遠く Dive in the Sky
Phase 16
Ignition
Fee, it was an accident.
Don't blame yourself.
（ユーリ）
フィー 事故だったんだ
自分を責めるな
今年は 11年に一度の太陽活動期だ
The sun is at the peak of its
11-year cycle this year.
Anyway, radio reception
was bad to begin with.
ただでさえ電波の通りが悪い
あのフレアは
誰にも予測できなかったし―
No one could have predicted
that solar flare.
フォローもできなかったよ
And they couldn't have done anything
about it even if they had.
As ship's captain, I'm responsible for
losing track of my crew during EVA.
（フィー）作業中のクルーを
ロストしたのは―
船長の私の責任だ
I should've anticipated a comm blackout based on...
通信途絶は―
プラズマ流の天象予報から
予測すべきだったし―
...the plasma flow information
in the space weather report.
I should've called off both
their jobs, not just Tanabe...
タナベだけじゃなく
ハチマキにも―
仕事の中断を
徹底すればよかったんだ
He wasn't exposed
for all that long.
（ユーリー）
暴露時間は それほどでもないんだ
He might not have been exposed
to lethal amounts of radiation.
命に関わるほどの放射線は…
（タナベ）あっ… 先輩は
先輩は大丈夫なんですか？
How is he?!
Is he going to be all right?!
何ともないってさ
They said that nothing's
wrong with me.
（３人）ええっ！？
The doctor was shocked, too!
I didn't catch much radiation at all.
いやあ お医者もビックリ
ほとんど被ばくしてねえの
なんか 俺
放射線のいちばんヤバいとき―
Looks like I was floating between the Van Allen
belts when the radiation was at its peak.
ヴァン･アレン帯の隙間に
入ってたみたいでさ
Besides, we were in
the Earth's shadow.
それに ほら
地球の影に入ってたじゃん 俺ら
He said that most people would've had their nervous systems fried by high-speed particles!
普通なら 超高速粒子に
神経 焼かれて おだぶつだって
They complimented me
on my dumb luck!
悪運 強いって 褒められたよ
アハハハ…
You've got some nerve
to be laughing!
（フィー）
どの面下げて笑ってんだ！
え？
（フィー）
元はといえば あんたが―
This whole mess happened because you missed your rendezvous with the target debris...
目標デブリとの
一時遭遇を逃して―
...and went chasing after it
like an idiot, right?!
深追いしたのが原因だろ？
And you let go
of your lifeline, too!
しかも 命綱まで勝手に外して
ひゃい ごめんなひゃあい
Yesh, ma'ab! I'b zorry!
（フィー）
今度 私の指示を無視したら―
You ignore my orders
like that again,
...and I'm gonna leave you out there
to join the debris, got it?!
そのまんま
デブリになってもらうからな
（タナベの泣き声）
For one thing, you...
大体…
（ハチマキ）ううっ
（タナベ）
よかった ほんと よかった
Thank goodness...
I'm so relieved...
I thought you were
going to die...
私 助からないかもって
悪かったな 心配させちまって
Yeah, sorry for making
you worry like that...
If that's the case, there will be a
vice president's position opening up.
（ノーマン）…となると―
常務の椅子が１つ 空きますな
The top candidate is probably
you-know-who.
（部長）最有力候補は
あの男なのでしょうね
We certainly can't complain about
the Second Division's record.
（専務）第２事業部の成績には
文句のつけようがない
So, we're finally looking at "Vice President Dolf," eh?
（銀行員）
ついにドルフ常務の誕生ですか
（ノーマン）冗談じゃない
You must be joking! Second Division owes its
record to the fact that he ignores the rules.
第２事業部の成績は
やつがルールを無視してるからだ
Well, he's certainly expanded our business
by breaking with tradition.
（部長）
まっ 確かに慣例を破ることで
彼は事業を拡大してきた
I'll give him that. Still, we can't build good
relations with INTO, not with his methods.
（専務）それは認めよう
しかし 彼のやり方では
連合といい関係は築けない
Meaning?
では…
I'll talk to the company president personally.
Your people won't have any objections, I take it?
会長には私から伝えよう
そちらも よろしいですな？
Banks are always on the side
of harmony and order.
銀行は 調和と秩序の味方ですから
Y'know, this goes beyond luck.
しかし あれだな
これは もう
ラッキーとかいう次元じゃねえな
Huh?
はあ？
Space loves me! I'm a man who won't die
before he completes his life's ambition!
俺は 宇宙に愛されている
大願を成すまで
死なない男なんだよ
Sure, sure...
はいはい
Go on, ask me!
Ask me what my life's ambition is.
聞けよ “大願って なあに？”って
マイ宇宙船でしょ？
何度も聞きましたよ
To own a spaceship, right?
You've told us that a million times.
Look here, you... When a man's talking about
his dreams, you just sit back and listen quietly.
お前な 男が夢を語るときは―
素直に聞くもんだろう
（看護師）星野(ほしの)さん
- Hoshino-san.
星野八郎太(はちろうた)さん
Hoshino Hachirota-san.
あ？ ああ 俺です
手続き 終わりました？
That's me.
Are my discharge papers ready?
I'm sorry, but we need to run
one more test.
（看護師）すみません
検査がもう１つ 残ってまして
Wha...?
（ハチマキ）はあ？
Would you mind going to the
Sensory Deprivation Chamber?
感覚遮断室まで
来ていただけますか？
Sure...
はあ
ああ… 何だってんだよ たく…
Damn it, what's
all this about?
"Sensory Deprivation Chamber" sounds a bit
ominous, but there's nothing to be afraid of.
（医師１）感覚遮断室なんて
怖そうな名前ですけど―
何のことはありません
ただの空っぽの部屋です
It's simply an empty room. With one difference.
一点を除いてね
We're ready
to begin.
（医師２）準備 終わりました
All right, here goes.
（医師１）じゃ 行きますよ
Yeah, fine.
はーい
This whole thing is stupid. What am I, a kid?
ばかばかしい 子供じゃあるまいし
As if an astronaut would be scared
of something like this...
こんなんが怖くて 宇宙飛行士が…
（タナベ）懐かしい
これ 研修でやりました
Wow, this takes me back!
I did this during training!
最初は 15分ももたなくて
I couldn't take it for more
than 15 minutes at first.
When I heard that you have to stay in
for 6 hours to get your EVA license,
でも
ＥＶＡのライセンス取るには―
６時間 耐えなくちゃ
ならないって聞いて―
...I nearly passed out.
気が遠くなっちゃいましたよ
（医師１）心拍数増加
（フィー･タナベ）えっ？
Heart rate climbing.
But it's only been
two minutes.
（ユーリ）まだ２分だぞ
Perspiration increasing.
Blood pressure climbing, too.
発汗量 増大
血圧も上昇しています
やはり
I thought as much.
When I read the incident report,
I thought this might be the case.
事故の報告書を読んで
もしかしたらとは思ったんですが
It's a condition that rarely
turns up in EVA workers.
船外作業員には
まれにある症状でしてね
（ハチマキの荒い息）
He was floating alone in space,
cut off from all communication, right?
（ハチマキの荒い息）
音信不通の宇宙に―
たった１人で
漂っていたんでしょ？
The terror he felt then has been
burned into his body.
そのときの恐怖を
体が覚えているんです
あっ…
Spatial Loss Disorder.
空間喪失症
Increase in blood pressure, rapid breathing,
panic, disorientation...
血圧上昇 過呼吸 パニック症状
方向感覚の喪失
There are sometimes even intense
visual and auditory hallucinations.
ひどいと幻覚や幻聴も起こる
If left untreated, it's a fatal blow
to an astronaut's career.
放っておけば
宇宙飛行士には 致命傷になります
（ユーリ･フィー）あっ…
（タナベ）ああ…
でたらめ抜かしやがって
あの野郎め！
That guy is full of crap! What a quack!
あの日はな
仕事の直後で疲れてたし―
It was right after work, so I was tired
that day! I hadn't eaten anything, either!
飯も食ってなかったんだ
They'll slap a name on anything
and call it a disease!
何にでも病名 付けやがって！
ハチマキ ごはん 飛んでる
Hachimaki, you're spitting
your food...
Anyway, I'm ready for 'em
this time!
とにかく 今度は万全だ
I'll stay in that room until I'm
nearly dead from starvation!
餓死寸前まで
あの部屋にいてやるぞ
見てろよ やぶ！
Just you watch,
you quack!
しゃあっ 行ってくる
Right! I'll be back later.
（タナベ）
先輩 大丈夫でしょうか？
Do you think Senpai's
gonna be okay?
Apparently, it's a psychological problem.
Whether or not he recovers is up to him.
心の問題だからな
回復は 本人しだいだそうだ
Well, with his spirit, I think he'll be fine.
He's an optimist.
まっ あの意気なら
問題なさそうかな
オプティミストだし
I guess you're right.
He's not that fragile a person.
そうですよね
そんな繊細な人じゃありませんよね
No, Hachimaki is an EVA specialist.
（ユーリ）いや ハチマキは
ＥＶＡスペシャリストだよ
If this turns out to be Spatial Loss Disorder,
his license will be revoked.
空間喪失症となれば
ライセンスは取り上げだ
えっ 取り上げって
Revoked?!
He'll never be able to go out
into space again.
（ユーリ）
二度と 宇宙には出られない
He has to be terrified
of that possibility.
それを恐れていないわけはないさ
はっ
（耳鳴り）
あっ
ぎゃあっ
（耳鳴り）
What the...?
（ハチマキ）何だあっ
（耳鳴り）
（ハチマキ）み… 耳が…
M-My ears!
The sound... It's inside... my head!
頭… 中で 音が…
T-The wall! Where's the wall?!
くっ… 壁… 壁はどこだ？
くっ ちくしょう
Son of a...
うわっ ぐうっ
うっ あああーっ！
ああっ
静(しず)かの海(うみ)総合病院に
連絡を取ってくれ
Get Sea of Tranquility General
Hospital on the phone!
Right away!
今すぐ
（ハチマキ）ハァ ハァ ハァ…
I knew it... Spatial Loss Disorder.
（医師）やはり 空間喪失症だ
So, is Hoshino's rehabilitation
coming along smoothly?
（ハキム）それで―
星野のリハビリは
順調に進んでいますか？
He's receiving medication and
mental training on the moon, but...
（クレア）
月で投薬とメンタルトレーニングを
でも…
I'm not optimistic
about his chances.
（ハキム）楽観はできませんね
心の問題ですから
After all,
it's all in his head.
ええ
Yes.
Are you worried
about him?
心配ですか？
I'm just... We're colleagues.
それは 同僚ですから
（ラビィ）ハァ…
How did it go, Lavie-chan?
（課長）
どうだった？ ラビィちゃん
The other departments should be able
to juggle their schedules to cover for us.
（ラビィ）各部署のスケジュールは
何とかなりそうですね
Should we go ahead and send
Fee-san and Yu-chan to the moon, then?
（課長）じゃ フィーさんと
ユーちゃんにも―
月に行ってもらおうか？
（ラビィ）そうですよね
I suppose so.
We can't take a break
like everyone else, though.
さすがに私たちまで
休むわけにはいきませんものね
（ユーリ）えっ あっ… ん ああ
（チェンシン）
ユーリさん 月 行くんですよね
Yuri-san, you're going
to the moon, right?
Right.
ああ 今週末
ハチマキの復帰試験があるからね
Hachimaki's reinstatement
test is this weekend.
Sorry to trouble you, but could you
give this to Hachimaki?
すいません ハチマキに これを
（ユーリ）ん？
（チェンシン）みんなから
かき集めたものですが―
It's a care package. We all pitched in.
あいつも
顔を合わせづらいだろうし―
He probably doesn't want to see anybody,
but could you give this to him for us?
お願いできますか？
ありがとう
Thank you.
（ギガルト）そうか
He is, huh? I had heard about it from Hakim,
but this sounds bad.
ハキムから聞いてはいたが
やっかいだな
今は タナベが付き添ってます
Tanabe's staying
with him now.
Spatial Loss Disorder is a psychological
sickness. He might have trouble getting over it.
（ギガルト）
空間喪失症は 心の病気だ
手こずるかもしれんぞ
I know. Depending on the test results,
he might be sent back to Earth.
はい
テストの結果しだいでは地球(オカ)に
Hachi won't be happy about it,
but there's no other way.
ハチは嫌がるでしょうけど
それしか…
うーん…
俺は医者じゃないが いい薬がある
I'm no doctor, but I know something
that might do the trick.
えっ？
We'll give it a shot.
一度 試してみろ
If he's a real astronaut, it should work
better than any stupid rehabilitation.
あいつが本物なら
下手なリハビリより効くはずだ
But if it doesn't, I won't
have any other choice.
だが もし それで駄目なようなら
しかたがない
I'll give him his dismissal
papers myself.
俺が直接 引導を渡そう
I'll have him...
あいつには…
ハチマキには 地球(オカ)に降りてもらう
I'll have Hachimaki
go back down to Earth.
I ran into the ninjas
before I came here.
（タナベ）ここに来る前
忍者さんたちに会ったんですよ
They say they have
jobs now.
就職できたんですって
At that test site on the
dark side of the moon.
月の裏側にある 何とかって実験場
You know, where they're building
the Von Braun's engine.
ほら フォン･ブラウン号の
エンジン 造ってるって
Yeah...
ああ
（アナウンス）
204号室の星野八郎太さん
Hoshino Hachirota-san of room 204,
preparations for your testing are now complete.
テストの準備が整いましたので
感覚遮断室まで お越しください
Please report to the Sensory Deprivation Chamber.
Hoshino Hachirota-san of room 204...
204号室の星野八郎太さん…
Senpai...
先輩
I've been in rehab for two weeks.
I'll be fine this time.
（ハチマキ）
半月もリハビリしたんだぞ
今度は大丈夫だって
Yeah... I'll be okay.
そうさ 大丈夫
（ノノ）あっ
Hachimaki? Is it time
for your test?
ハチマキ テストなの？
Oh... Uh... Yeah.
（ハチマキ）お… あっ ああ
じゃ 医者 待ってるし
See you later. The doctor's waiting.
ごめんね ノノちゃん
テストが終わったらね
Sorry, Nono-chan. We can talk
after the test is over.
うん テスト 大事だもんね
Sure. Tests are important.
（医師）開始します
Let's begin.
おう！
Yeah!
I've taken my medicine.
薬も飲んだ リハビリもした
I've been through rehab.
休養も取った
I'm rested up, too.
I can't possibly fail
a simple test like this.
こんな初歩的なテスト
できないはずがないんだ
（波の音）
（ハチマキ）うっ あっ
The sea? Where am I?
海？ ここは… あっ
ああ…
That's me!
俺だ
Then, this is...
じゃ ここは…
うわっ
ぐああーっ！
（ハチマキ）何だ？ これ
What is this?
What is all this?!
何だよ？ これ
そうだ 俺は…
Oh, right... I'm a...
（ハチマキ）あっ
Now I remember...
（ハチマキ）そうだよ
I'm an astronaut. A debris hauler.
俺は宇宙飛行士で デブリ屋で
あっ
Who's there?!
誰だ！
You felt it, didn't you? While you were
drifting in that radiation storm.
（宇宙飛行士）感じたんだろ？
放射線の嵐を漂いながら
Say what?
（ハチマキ）何だと！
"I might die out here."
（宇宙飛行士）
くたばるかもしれないって
But that thought actually came as a relief.
でも 本当は
救われる気分だったろ？
What're you talking about?
（ハチマキ）何言ってやがる
人間その気になりゃあ
結婚だろうが 宇宙船だろうがよ
If a man puts his mind to it, he can get married
or even buy a spaceship!
ああっ
Hey, is that him? The idiot who says
he's gonna buy his own ship?
（社員）おい あいつか？
宇宙船 買うってバカは
（シア）
おにいちゃん 宇宙船 買った？
Did you buy your
spaceship yet, mister?
I thought you said you were gonna work
hard until you had your own spaceship!
マイ宇宙船 手に入れるまで
頑張るって言ったじゃないですか
先輩の夢なんでしょ？ 宇宙船
Isn't getting a spaceship
your dream, Senpai?
You know, don't you?
（宇宙飛行士）分かってるんだろ？
一介の
デブリ屋にすぎない自分が―
You know a lowly junk jockey like you
will never get his own spaceship.
宇宙船なんて
手に入れられるはずがないって
Don't tell me what I can't do!
I'll get one, no matter what!
勝手に決めつけるな！
俺は 絶対…
（ハチマキ）
分かってる もう分かってんだ
I understand... It's all clear now.
A lowly debris collector could work for decades
and still not be able to buy a real spaceship.
宇宙船なんてな―
たかだか デブリ屋が
何十年 働いたところで―
本物は買えやしねえってな！
はっ… くっ…
（ハチマキ）俺が
宇宙船 買ったら おかしいか？
Is me buying a spaceship
that funny?
宇宙船も
まだ手に入れてないってのに
Damn it, I haven't even gotten
my spaceship yet...
（宇宙飛行士）フッフッフッ…
それでも ほえ続けたのは―
The reason you kept spouting
that crap was because...
...you wanted to stay in
your little dream world.
いつまでも
夢の途中でいたかったからさ なあ
Right?
Screw you! I still haven't...
うるさい！ 俺は まだ…
Having dreams that are too big
will ruin a man.
（宇宙飛行士）
大きすぎる夢は身を滅ぼすぞ
Even you have to realize that. Even you.
分かっているだろう？ お前には
That's right. You've seen it.
そう 見てきた
You've seen how it always ends.
見てきたはずだ お前は
その最後まで
You've heard the expression
"know your limitations," haven't you?
分相応って言葉が
お前の耳にも聞こえるんだろ？
（ハチマキ）くっ…
ようやく 人を乗せて
飛べるようになったんだ
They're finally letting me
carry people now.
Let it go. Any more of this, and you'll make us
think that you have an inferiority complex.
（コリン）やめなよ
それ以上 言うと ひがみになるよ
（九太郎(きゅうたろう)）中途半端にカッコつけて
適当なところに落ち着いて
Sure, you talk the talk, but you settled down
and got complacent the first chance you got!
（宇宙飛行士）戦いきれないお前は
今頃になって―
You can't fight your way though, so now you're
finally starting to look for an excuse.
ようやく言い訳を探し始めている
An excuse?!
言い訳だと？
Me?
俺が？ 俺が…
No way!
It's true.
（宇宙飛行士）そうだ
This sickness of yours
is exactly what you wanted.
お前の病は お前が望んだんだぜ
（ハチマキ）あっ 俺！？
Me?
Families? Why are you
showing me this?
（ハチマキ）家族… どうして
俺にこんなものを見せる？
I'll leave them love!
愛です！
Tanabe?
（ハチマキ）タナベ！
（タナベ）１人で生きて
１人で死んで １人で…
Living alone
and dying alone...
Alone...
なんで満足できるんですか？
バカみたい
How could anyone
be satisfied with that?
It's stupid.
She's cute, isn't she?
（八郎太）
かわいいじゃないか？ 彼女
It's not so bad.
悪くない そう 悪くないよな
こういうのも
No, it doesn't sound so bad.
Go down to Earth, get married,
grow old...
地球(オカ)に降りて 結婚して 年食って
Shut up!
（ハチマキ）黙れ！
（八郎太）フフフフ…
夜空の輝きを見上げながら―
You wanted the right to look up at the
lights in the night sky and say,
“あの病気さえなければ
今頃 俺は”
..."If it wasn't for that sickness,
I'd still be up there right now."
そう言える権利を
お前は欲したんだ
"I didn't give up or anything. It's not my fault."
“諦めたわけじゃない
俺のせいじゃない”
"It was because
of that accident."
“あの事故が悪いんだ”
"If it wasn't for that accident, I know I'd..."
“あれさえなければ
俺だって きっと”
（課長）わあっ
ちゃんと答えてください！
あっ
（ハチマキ）はあ…
父ちゃんより食うんじゃねえの？
It's for the best.
（八郎太）
いいじゃないか？ これで
Like hell! Shut the hell up!
うるせえ！ 黙れ！
Admit it. Accept reality.
Make it easy for yourself.
認めろ 受け入れて楽になって
うそをわびるんだ
Apologize for lying
to yourself.
黙れ 黙れーっ！
Shut up! Shut up!
Space might not love you,
but it will forgive you.
宇宙は お前を愛してはくれないが
許してはくれる
Shut the hell up!
黙れーっ！
くうっ
があっ ああ…
（ハチマキ）ああっ…
Senpai!
先輩！
（医師１）救護班を呼べ
Get a medical team
in here!
A stretcher! Go get a stretcher!
（医師２）担架だ 担架の用意を！
♪～
（タナベ）先輩って
結構 落ち込みやすいんですね
You sure get depressed easily,
you know that?
私には いろいろ言うくせに
And after all those speeches
you've given to me...
Still, you're able to stay
in there longer now, right?
でも だんだん長く―
耐えられるように
なってきたじゃないですか
The rehab must be working.
You were in there a whole 20 minutes today.
リハビリの効果ですね
今日なんて 20分も…
あっ…
フィーさんとユーリさんから
連絡がありました
I got a message from Fee-san and Yuri-san.
They're in Tranquility City right now,
so they should be here pretty soon.
今はトランクルシティーだから
もう少しで こっちに着くって
先輩 地球に戻ったほうが
いいんじゃないですか？
Senpai... Maybe it would be better
if you went back to Earth.
（ハチマキ）あっ…
You could breathe fresh air
and tackle this nice and slowly.
（タナベ）おいしい空気 吸って
じっくり取り組んだほうが
Let me handle the Fishbone
while you're away.
先輩がいない間
フィッシュボーンは任せてください
I'm pretty good
at the job now.
私だって
随分 使えるようになったんですよ
It's okay, space isn't
going anywhere.
大丈夫 宇宙は逃げませんよ
There's always gonna be lots of debris
that will need to be brought in.
拾わなくちゃいけないデブリだって
山ほど…
あっ 先輩
Senpai?
Senpai!
先輩？
That's right, Hoshino Hachirota.
（フィー）そう 星野八郎太
He's been
checked in here since last month.
先月から入院してるはずだけど？
Tanabe!
（ユーリ）タナベ
（タナベ）ユーリさん
Yuri-san!
Good timing. We were just...
ちょうどよかった 俺たち 今…
（タナベ）先輩が…
（ユーリ･フィー）お？
It's Senpai!
He's missing!
先輩がいなくなっちゃったんです
（ユーリ･フィー）ええっ！？
This is a page for Hoshino-san
of room 204.
（アナウンス）
お呼び出し申し上げます
204号室の星野さん
星野八郎太さん
Hoshino Hachirota-san.
Hoshino Hachirota-san of room 204,
please come to the reception desk at once.
204号室の星野八郎太さん
至急 受付までおいでください
Nono-chan! Have you
seen Hachimaki?
ノノちゃん
ハチマキ先輩 見なかった？
ううん どうかしたの？
No, sorry. Is something wrong?
He's missing!
（タナベ）いなくなっちゃったの
（ノノ）ええっ
He hasn't gone through the gate,
so I think he's still in the hospital.
ゲートは通ってないみたいだから
病院の中だと思うんだけど
あっ
何？ 心当たりあるの？
What is it? Do you know where he is?
Maybe... Maybe he's over there.
ひょっとして―
あそこかもしれない
（ハチマキ）
ハァ ハァ ハァ ハァ…
You gotta be kidding me!
I'll never get better on Earth!
冗談じゃねえぞ
地球(オカ)じゃあ 治せるわけがねえ
あっ
Senpai...
（タナベ）先輩
Damn it...
ちきしょう ああっ…
I wanna stay
in space...
俺はまだ 宇宙に…
No way am I gonna let everything
I've worked for go down the tubes...
今までのこと
全部 無駄にして たまるか
I won't!
俺は…
Senpai, stop it!
先輩 もうやめてください！
Please!
お願いです
I'll never go into
space again...
もう二度と…
自殺行為だ それで特訓のつもり？
This is suicide.
Or is this some kind of special training?
Screw you!
うるさい！
I seem to recall an astronaut who died
out here on the surface of the moon.
（フィー）そうやって
月面で死んだ宇宙飛行士がいたわね
Well, maybe that's better than living
with a lifetime of regret.
まっ 無念の人生を
続けていくよりは いいかもね
（ハチマキ）ぐっ…
Still, you aren't in such
a hurry to die...
でも チームメートのおせっかいに
つきあえないほど―
...that you can't put up with a little meddling
from your teammates, are you?
死に急いでるわけじゃ
ないんでしょ？
（フィー）見学許可を取るのに
随分 苦労したんだからね
It took a lot of doing to
get these visitor's permits.
Gigalt-san said this might be just
what the doctor ordered.
ギガルトさんが あんたには
いい薬になるかもしれないって
He said that?
先生が？
よく来たな 星野
Glad you could
make it, Hoshino.
あっ… ハキム
Hakim?
Thanks. I guess we're making
a lot of trouble for you.
ありがと 手数をかけるわね
Don't mention it. We're both students
of the Gigalt School.
いえ
同じギガルト学校の生徒ですから
あっ…
（フィー）見ておきなさい ハチ
Feast your eyes on this, Hachi.
冥土の土産としても
なかなかのもんよ
A little something to take
with you to the afterlife.
The tandem mirror
nuclear fusion engine.
タンデムミラー式 核融合エンジン
The most powerful engine
ever built.
世界最強のエンジンよ
It uses the deuterium-helium 3
fusion reaction to generate thrust.
（ユーリ）重水素と
ヘリウム３の核融合反応を―
推進力にするんだ
反応室内で生まれた
５億度の高速荷電粒子は―
High-speed, charged particles
are generated inside
the fusion chamber at 500 million
degrees Celsius.
磁場でコントロールされて―
They are controlled by means
of magnetic fields,
推進剤と一緒に
ノズルから放出される
...and released along with propellant
from its nozzle in back.
飛推力は 60万秒
It has a specific impulse
of 600,000 seconds.
That's about 10,000 times greater than our own ship's.
俺たちの船の約１万倍だ
（フィー）木星往還船―
This is the main engine that will be mounted
in the Jupiter explorer, the Von Braun.
フォン･ブラウン号に搭載される
メインエンジン
If we can use this to develop the Jovian system,
it will make a great fuel supply center.
（ユーリ）
こいつで木星系が開発されれば―
いい燃料供給地になる
Before too long, astronauts are
going to have their hands full.
この先 宇宙飛行士は忙しくなるな
The solar system
is going to change.
太陽系は変わるぞ
At times like this,
the world needs fools.
こういうときは バカが必要なんだ
It needs people
like you.
あんたみたいなやつがね
（ハチマキ）ああ…
You seem relaxed today.
（八郎太）
落ち着いてるじゃないか？ 今日は
Let me ask you something.
What have you decided?
聞こう どう決断したんだ？
別に 大して今までと変わりないさ
Nah, I'm not really any
different from before.
ああ いや ちょっと違うな
No, I take that back. Maybe I have changed a little.
考えたんだ 俺
Something occurred
to me.
あのエンジンを造った
エンジニアたちも―
Maybe the engineers who built that engine
also had to fight things like you.
あんたみたいのと
ケンカしたことあるのかなって
There in the darkness, blind, groping along
and trying to find their way,
何も見えない暗闇の中で
手探りで道を探して
きっとみんな
そういう思いをしてきたはずなんだ
...I bet they all went through
that same experience.
ツィオルコフスキーも
ゴダードも―
Even Tsiolkovsky. And Goddard.
And Oberth. And Von Braun.
オーベルトも フォン･ブラウンも
But once I swore to myself that
I'd fight you my whole life,
でも あんたとのケンカを―
一生かけてするって
腹を決めれば―
いつか光は差すんだ
...I knew I'd see
the light eventually.
今は去ろう
I'll go for now. But don't let
your guard down, Hachimaki.
だが気を抜くなよ ハチマキ
I might come back when
you least expect me.
俺は いつでも現れるぞ
Test cleared.
（医師）テストクリア
Senpai!
先輩！
（タナベの泣き声）
You do that.
買ってやるよ
I'll be ready for you.
そのケンカ
♪～
♪グッと水を飲み干し
gutto mizu wo nomihoshi
We gulp down some water
yuuyakegumo miageru no sa
and look up at the evening clouds.
♪夕焼け雲見上げるのさ
♪今日も一日が終わって
kyou mo ichinichi ga owatte
Let's wind our way home under the roadside trees as another day ends.
♪街路樹の下を帰ろう
gairoju no shita wo kaerou
yaru koto darake de tenpatte
Even if life's so hectic that our tempers flare,
♪やることだらけで
テンパって、
♪無理をして、
つまずいても
muri wo shite tsumazuite mo
we push ourselves too hard, and we stumble,
♪何か必ず
つかんでるさ
nani ka kanarazu tsukanderu sa
I know there'll be something to grab hold of.
♪気楽にいこうぜ
kiraku ni ikou ze
Let's move on without a care in our hearts.
♪素晴らしい人生だから
subarashii jinsei dakara
It's a wonderful life.
♪自分を愛する
勇気を持とう
jibun wo aisuru yuuki wo motou
So let's have the courage to love ourselves.
♪新しいドア叩いて
atarashii doa tataite
Let's take it one step at a time,
♪ひとつひとつ
歩いてゆこう
hitotsu hitotsu aruite yukou
knocking on new doors on the way.
♪素晴らしい人生なのさ
subarashii jinsei na no sa
It's a wonderful life.
♪君も僕もすべての人も
kimi mo boku mo subete no hito mo
You and I and everyone else
♪喜びと悲しみの意味
yorokobi to kanashimi no imi
Keep on searching for the meaning
♪探しつづけて
so just on my way
sagashitsuzukete so just on my way
Of joy and sadness, so just on my way.
Next Time
His Reasons
Okay, you can
come out now.
よっ
もう出てきていいぞ
Hey! How have you been,
dumb son o' mine?
（ゴロー）よう！
元気でやってたか？
バカ息子
（会長）
バカは 困りますよ
A fool in that position...
will cause us trouble.
Talk about a
self-centered boss...
（紅右近(くれないうこん)）
わがままなボスだな
But he doesn't know the meaning
of the word harmony.
（専務）
調和という言葉を知らない
And whose fault
is that?
（クレア）これは
誰のせいなのかしらね
You said it to me once,
remember?
君 前に言ってただろ？
（ロックスミス）
私が宇宙船以外―
Because I'm a man of exceptional talent who is...
何ひとつ愛せないという
逸材だからさ
...incapable of loving anything but spaceships.
変なこと言うなよ
セクハラじじい
Keep your comments to yourself,
you sleazy old geezer!